Muhammad Mazhar

LAHORE

m.mazharwattoo@gmail.com

+92.343.0012556

I am a full stack .NET developer having over all three years experience in development .I have expertise in following tools

and technologies SharePoint, Asp.net mvc, Desktop Application development, Asp.net core, Restful Web API, Web

scraping, SSRS Reporting, JavaScript, and fronted technologies like HTML, CSS, Bootstrap etc. I am passoniate to learn new tools and technologies related to Machine learning and Data science.

Work Experience

Software Engineer-contract based

Animal Quarantine Department Lahore - Lahore, PK November 2019 to Present

Govt of Pakistan, Lahore, Pakistan

"The Animal Quarantine Department (AQD) is an attached department of Ministry of National Food Security & Research.

AQD provide's quarantine, inspection and certification services at seven different locations across Pakistan".

AQD is my client. I am develping an window based application for managing their Import & Export certificates and intenal document management system.

Software Engineer

Ghost Digital & Data (GD&D) - Lahore, PK July 2019 to Present

Pakistan

Participate in requirements analysis

Collaborate with internal teams to produce software design and architecture

Write clean, scalable code using .NET programming languages

Test and deploy applications and systems

Revise, update, refactor and debug code

Improve existing software

Serve as an expert on applications and provide technical support

ASP.NET Developer

Originator IT Solution - Lahore, PK January 2019 to June 2019

Pakistan

Utilize established development tools, guidelines and conventions including but not limited to ASP.NET, SQL Server, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and C#/VB.NET

Prepare and maintain code for various .Net applications and resolve any defects in systems.

Prepare test based applications for various .Net applications.

Enhance existing systems by analyzing business objectives,

preparing an action plan and identifying areas for modification and improvement

Manage defect tracking system and resolve all issues and prepare update for

systems. Investigate and develop skills in new technologies

Create technical specifications and test plans Monitor everyday activities of system and provide require support.

Email Marketing Specialist

Email Marketing - Lahore, PK August 2018 to February 2019

Pakistan

Here my responsibility were to collect Email Id using Different website and tools and then send Emails of Our Business Services.

Program Coordinator

EVS Professional Training Institute - Lahore, PK August 2015 to March 2018

Pakistan

Manage all daily Tasks Coordinates with students coordinates with instructors Social Media Marketing Fee collection and management

Education

Bachelor's in Computer Science

PAF IT Academy Lahore - Lahore September 2015 to July 2019

Intermediate in Computer Science

Govt.College Gulburg - Lahore, Pakistan August 2013 to May 2015

High School in Science

Govt Higher Secondary School - Mandi Ahmad Okara, Punjab Pakistan March 2010 to April 2012

Skills

- Python
- ASP.NET MVC

- C# Programming
- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- SQL Server
- Entity Framework
- Restful Web API
- Git Version Control System
- Azure Devops
- Agile Software Development Life Cycle
- · Object Oriented programming
- SharePoint

Languages

- English Intermediate
- Urdu Fluent
- Punjabi Fluent

Links

https://github.com/EVSMAZHAR

https://www.kaggle.com/muhammadmazhar1

https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-mazhar-099b4a102/

Certifications and Licenses

Microsoft Technologies Assosiate

February 2021 to Present

Certified .NET Developer

August 2016 to Present

C#, ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, Front End Development, Web API

Artificial Intelligence

March 2020 to Present

Artificial Intelligence, Computer Vision, Robotics/Machine Learning, DATA SCIENCE, Linux, Deep Learning, Git

Introduction to Data science Module 1

January 2021 to Present

Python Programming, Numpy, Pandas, Data analysis, Data Visualization

Python Programming - kaggle

February 2020 to Present

Python Programming, Data Structure

Pandas - kaggle

August 2020 to Present

Introduction to Numpy, pandas, Data Analysis

Data Visualization - kaggle

September 2020 to Present

Data Visualization

Introduction To Machine Learning

October 2020 to Present

Introduction to machine Learning , Supervised learning, Unsupervised Learning , reinforcement learning

Intermediate Machine Learning- Kaggle

November 2020 to Present

machine learning Pipeline, corss validation techniques, data reangling,...

Introduction to deep Learning - Kaggle

March 2021 to Present

Neural Networks, layers, tensor flow, Pipeline ..